Sigmund Freud Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Oversize, 1859-1985 (Box OV 1-OV 20)
  - Writings* (Container 50A) (Box OV 2, Reel 1)
    - 1886
      - “Beobachtung einer hochgradigen Hemianästhesie bei einem hysterischen Manne (Beiträge zur Kasuistik der Hysterie I),” with published response by Leopold Königstein [d]
        - Negative photocopy of printed publication
        - Offprint
        - Offprint inscribed by Freud to Josef Breuer, printed publication and photocopy of same
    - 1887
      - “Kritische Einleitung in die Nervenpathologie,” photocopy of holograph manuscript
    - 1892
      - “Probleme” [Draft A],* holograph manuscript
        *Draft writings identified partially with a bracketed alphabetical designation from “A” to “N” refer to early Freud manuscripts as described and published in The Complete Letters of Sigmund Freud to Wilhelm Fliess, 1887-1904 (Cambridge, Mass.: Belknap Press of Harvard University Press, 1985), translated and edited by J. Moussaieff Masson.
    - 1892-1894
      - [Translation of lectures by J. M. Charcot], holograph manuscripts described as Lecture I, pp. 12-13 (sheets 15-16), Lecture XVII, pp. 195-201 (sheets 11-22), and Lecture XVIII, pp. 202-208 (sheets 1-11)
    - 1893
      - “Die Aetiologie der Neurosen” [Draft B], holograph manuscript
      - “Etwas Motivenbericht” [Draft C], holograph manuscript
    - circa 1893
      - [Ten points on the origin of hysterical manifestations], holograph manuscript with photocopy
    - 1894
      - “Zur Aetiologie und Theorie der grossen Neurosen” [Draft D], holograph manuscript
      - “Wie die Angst entsteht” [Draft E], holograph manuscript
      - “Sammlung III” [Draft F], photocopy of holograph manuscript
      - [Notes on a manuscript by Wilhelm Fliess], photocopy of holograph manuscript and typed transcript
    - 1895
      - “Melancholie” [Draft G], holograph manuscript
      - “Paranoia” [Draft H], holograph manuscript
      - “Migraine feste Punkte” [Draft I], photocopy of holograph manuscript (2 copies)
      - “Frau Regine Kunn 27 J[ahre]” [Draft J], redacted photocopy of holograph manuscript
    - 1896
      - “ Die Abwehrneurosen (Weihnachtsmärchen)” [Draft K], holograph manuscript
    - 1897
      - [Draft L], with letter to Wilhelm Fliess, 1897, May 2, holograph manuscript
      - “Architektur der Hysterie” [Draft M], holograph manuscript
      - [Draft N], with letter to Wilhelm Fliess, 1897, May 31, holograph manuscript
    - 1897-1898
      - [Collection of notes on various subjects, beginning “Aus älteren Aufzeichnungen von 1897 an”], holograph manuscripts with photocopies and typewritten transcriptions
        - I-A
        - II-A
        - III-A
    - 1898, "Die Sexualität in der Aetiologie der Neurosen," Wiener Klinische Rundschau, printed publication
    - 1901
      - [“Zur Psychopathologie des Alltagslebens”] [b]
        - [“III: Vergessen vom Namen und Wortfolgen”], holograph manuscript (numbered 1-10 with an additional page) with photocopy
        - [IV: “Über Kindheits- und Deckerinnerungen”], holograph manuscript (numbered 1-5) with photocopy
    - 1904-1905
      - [Notes on diverse subjects, including on the psychology of human love], holograph manuscript with photocopy
    - 1906
      - “Professor Sigmund Freud” [“Antwort auf eine Rundfrage”] [f], photocopy of printed publication
    - 1907
      - “Der Wahn und die Träume in W. Jensen's 'Gradiva'” [a], photocopies from 1907 and 1908 published editions and transcript of “Anzeige” from 1907 edition
      - “Zur sexuellen Aufklärung der Kinder” [c], holograph manuscript
    - 1908
      - “Charakter und Analerotik” [b], holograph manuscript
      - “Über infantile Sexualtheorien” [c], holograph manuscript
      - “Die 'kulturelle' Sexualmoral and die moderne Nervosität” [d], holograph manuscript (Box OV 3, Reel 1)
    - 1909
      - “Allgemeines über den hysterischen Anfall” [a] [1908], holograph manuscript
      - “Bemerkungen über einen Fall von Zwangsneurose” [d] [Rat Man], holograph manuscript
        - Folder 1, pp. 1-40
        - Folder 2, pp. 41-77
      - “Reisejournal, [Aug. 21-24]” holograph manuscript and partial transcript
    - 1909-1910
      - [Notes on dreams and dream symbols with first page titled “3 Sammelbögen,” 1909, Apr. 20], holograph manuscripts with photocopies
    - 1910
      - “Über die Entstehung und Entwicklung der Psychoanalyse” [“Über Psychoanalyse”] [a] [1909], holograph manuscript
        - Folder 1, pp. 1-31
        - Folder 2, pp. 32-52
      - “Eine Kindheitserinnerung des Leonardo da Vinci” [c], holograph manuscript
        - Folder 1, pp. 1-32
        - Folder 2, pp. 33-66
      - “Über den Gegensinn der Urworte” [e], holograph manuscript
      - “Zur Einleitung der Selbstmord-Diskussion. Schlusswort” [g], holograph manuscript
      - “Beiträge zur Psychologie des Liebeslebens: Über einen besonderen Typus der Objektwahl beim Manne” [h], holograph manuscript
    - 1911
      - “Sammlung zum Traum,” 1911, Dec. 12, holograph manuscript
      - “Nachträge zur Traumdeutung” [a], holograph manuscript and clipping with handwritten note
      - “Formulierungen über die zwei Prinzipien des psychischen Geschehens” [b], holograph manuscript
      - “Psychoanalytische Bemerkungen über einen autobiographisch beschriebenen Fall von Paranoia (Dementia Paranoides)” [c] [Schreber case], holograph manuscript
        - Folder 1, pp. 1-34
        - Folder 2, pp. 35-74
      - “Die Handhabung der Traumdeutung in der Psychoanalyse” [e], holograph manuscript
    - 1911-1913
      - “Ideen u[nd] Entdeckungen,” holograph manuscript with photocopy
    - 1912-1913 (Box OV 4, Reel 2)
      - “Über einige Übereinstimmungen im Seelenleben der Wilden und der Neurotiker” [“Totem und Tabu”] [a]
        - [Miscellaneous manuscripts], holograph manuscripts with photocopies
        - “II: Das Tabu und die Ambivalenz der Gefühlsregungen,” photocopy of holograph manuscript
          - Folder 1, pp. 22-38
          - Folder 2, pp. 39-55
          - Folder 3, pp. 56-71
        - “III: Animismus, Magie und Allmacht der Gedanken,” holograph manuscript
        - “IV: Die infantile Wiederkehr des Totemismus,” holograph manuscript
          - Folder 1, pp. 1-32
          - Folder 2, pp. 33-77
        - [Bibliographic notes], holograph manuscripts with photocopies
          - Folder 1
          - Folder 2
    - 1913
      - “Ein Traum als Beweismittel” [a], holograph manuscript
      - “Weitere Ratschläge zur Technik der Psychoanalyse: I, Zur Einleitung der Behandlung” [c], holograph manuscript
      - “Das Motiv der Kästchenwahl” [f], holograph manuscript
      - “Zwei Kinderlügen” [g], holograph manuscript
      - “Die Disposition zur Zwangsneurose” [i], holograph manuscript
    - 1914
      - “Über fausse reconnaissance ('déjà raconté') während der psychoanalytischen Arbeit” [a], holograph manuscript
      - “Der Moses des Michelangelo” [b], holograph manuscript with ink sketch of Michelangelo's “Moses”
      - “Zur Einführung des Narzissmus” [c], holograph manuscript
      - “Zur Psychologie des Gymnasiasten” [f], photocopy of printed publication
      - “Zur Geschichte der psychoanalytischen Bewegung” [d], holograph manuscript
        - Folder 1, pp. 1-36
        - Folder 1, pp. 37-71
      - “Weitere Ratschläge zur Technik der Psychoanalyse: II, Erinnern, Wiederholen und Durcharbeiten” [g], holograph manuscript (Box OV 5, Reel 2)
      - [Various notes on “Macbeth,” 1914, July ], holograph manuscripts with photocopies
    - 1915
      - “Bemerkungen über die Übertragungsliebe” [“Weitere Ratschläge zur Technik der Psychoanalyse: III”] [a], holograph manuscript
      - “Zeitgemässes über Krieg und Tod” [b], holograph manuscript
      - “Triebe und Triebschicksale” [c], holograph manuscript
      - “Die Verdrängung” [d], holograph manuscript
      - “Das Unbewusste” [e], holograph manuscript
      - “Mitteilung eines der psychoanalytischen Theorie widersprechenden Falles von Paranoia” [f], holograph manuscript
      - [Letter to Dr. F. van Eeden] [ 1914 ] [g], corrected and signed typewritten proof and photocopy of holograph manuscript
      - “Wir und der Tod” [ 1915, Feb. 7 ] [i], holograph manuscript with photocopy
      - [Letter dated 1915, Feb. 7, on melancholia], holograph manuscript
    - [1915], "Traum vom 8/9 Juli Dr/Fr 3/4 2 beim Erwachen," holograph manuscript with typed transcript
    - 1916
      - “Mythologische Parallele zu einer plastischen Zwangsvorstellung” [b], holograph manuscript
      - “Eine Beziehung zwischen einem Symbol und einem Symptom” [c], holograph manuscript
      - “Einige Charaktertypen aus der psychoanalytischen Arbeit” [d], holograph manuscript (Box OV 6, Reel 3)
    - 1916-1917
      - “Vorlesungen zur Einführung in die Psychoanalyse” [a]
        - [“I Teil: Die Fehlleistungen (I-IV)”], holograph manuscript
          - Folder 1, pp. 1-40
          - Folder 2, pp. 41-72
        - [“II Teil: Der Traum,” begins “Fünfte Vorlesung”], holograph manuscript
          - Folder 1, pp. 1-34
          - Folder 2, pp. 35-72
          - Folder 3, pp. 73-108
          - Folder 4, pp. 109-140
          - Folder 5, pp. 141-174
        - “Neurosenlehre: I. Psychoanalyse und Psychiatrie” [“Vorlesungen zur Einführung in die Psychoanalyse: III Teil: Allgemeine Neurosenlehre”], holograph manuscript
          - Folder 1, pp. 1-28
          - Folder 2, pp. 29-68
          - Folder 3, pp. 69-108
          - Folder 4, pp. 109-140
          - Folder 5, pp. 141-174
          - Folder 6, pp. 175-214
          - Folder 7, pp. 215-251
    - 1917
      - “Eine Schwierigkeit der Psychoanalyse” [a], holograph manuscript
      - “Eine Kindheitserinnerung aus Dichtung und Wahrheit ” [b], holograph manuscript
      - “Über Triebumsetzungen, insbesondere der Analerotik” [c], holograph manuscript
      - “Metapsychologische Ergänzung zur Traumlehre” [d], holograph manuscript
      - “Trauer und Melancholie” [1915] [e], holograph manuscript
    - 1918
      - “Beiträge zur Psychologie des Liebeslebens: Das Tabu der Virginität” [a], holograph manuscript
      - “Aus der Geschichte einer infantilen Neurose” [b] [Wolf-Man case], holograph manuscript (Box OV 7, Reel 3)
        - Folder 1, pp. 1-32
        - Folder 2, pp. 33-60
        - Folder 3, pp. 61-90
        - Folder 4, pp. 91-116
      - “Sammlung kleiner Schriften zur Neurosenlehre, vierte folge”
        - Original and photocopies of title page and table of contents
        - Corrected galley proofs, pp. 449-480 (pp. 465-480 are misnumbered as 365-380), 1918, Aug., printed publication
    - 1919
      - “Wege der psychoanalytischen Therapie” [a], holograph manuscript
      - “James J. Putnam” [b], holograph manuscript
      - “Zur psychoanalytischer Bewegung. Internationaler psychoanalytischer Verlag und Preiszuteilungen für psychoanalytische Arbeiten” [c], holograph manuscript
      - “Vorwort” [“Einleitung zu Zur Psychoanalyse der Kriegsneurosen ”] [d], holograph manuscript
      - “Ein Kind wird geschlagen, Beitrag zur Kenntnis der Entstehung sexueller Perversionen” [e], holograph manuscript
      - “Vorrede” [“Vorrede zu Reik Probleme der Religionpsychologie ”] [g], holograph manuscript
      - “Das Unheimliche” [h], holograph manuscript
    - 1920
      - “Über die Psychogenese eines Falles von weiblicher Homosexualität” [a] [Trautenegg case], holograph manuscript
      - “Zur Vorgeschichte der analytischen Technik” [b], holograph manuscript
      - “Dr. Anton v. Freund” [c], holograph manuscript
      - “Gedankenassoziation eines 4 jährigen Kindes” [“Gedan-kenassoziation eines vierjährigen Kindes”] [d], holograph manuscript
      - “Vorwort zur vierten Auflage [der Drei Abhandlungen zur Sexualtheorie ]” [e]
        - Holograph manuscript
        - Typewritten manuscript with holograph corrections and additions with photocopy and holograph reaction to essay not in Freud's hand
      - “Jenseits des Lustprinzips” [g]
        - Holograph manuscript
        - Holograph and typewritten manuscript, bound
    - 1921
      - [“Massenpsychologie und Ich-Analyse”] [c], photocopies of holograph manuscripts
    - 1922
      - “Traum und Telepathie” [a], holograph and typewritten manuscripts
      - “Über einige neurotische Mechanismen bei Eifersucht, Paranoia und Homosexualität” [b], holograph manuscript
      - “Nachschrift zur Analyse des kleinen Hans” [c], holograph manuscript (Box OV 8, Reel 4)
      - “Geleitwort” [“Preface (in French) to Raymond de Saussure's 'La méthode psychoanalytique'”] [e], holograph manuscript with photocopy and typewritten transcript
      - “Teufelsverschreibung,” original and photocopy of holograph manuscript
      - “Dream and Telepathy” [a], typewritten English translation by Wilson Vance with corrections not in Freud's hand but signed by him and holograph comments by Freud
    - 1923
      - “Libido Theorie” [a], holograph manuscript
      - “Das Ich und das Es” [b]
        - Holograph manuscript
          - Folder 1
          - Folder 2
        - Published copy by Internationaler Psychoanalytischer Verlag, 1923, original (lacks covers and spine) with occasional pencilled notes not in Freud's hand and photocopy
          - Original
          - Photocopy
      - “Bemerkungen zur Theorie und Praxis der Traumdeutung” [c], holograph manuscript
      - “Eine Teufelsneurose im siebzehnten Jahrhundert” [1922] [d], holograph manuscripts with photocopies
        - Folder 1
        - Folder 2
        - Folder 3
        - Folder 4
        - Folder 5
      - “Die infantile Genitalorganisation (Eine Einschaltung in die Sexualtheorie)” [e], holograph manuscript
      - “Dr. Ferenczi Sándor” [i], typewritten transcript and photocopy of holograph manuscript
      - [“Preface to Max Eitingon's Bericht über die Berliner psychoanalytische Poliklinik ”] [g], holograph manuscript
    - 1924
      - “Neurose und Psychose” [b], holograph manuscript
      - “Das ökonomische Problem des Masochismus” [c], holograph manuscript
      - “Der Untergang des Ödipuskomplexes” [d], holograph manuscript
      - “Die Geschichte der Psychoanalyse” [“Kurzer Abriss der Psychoanalyse”] [1923] [f], holograph manuscript (Box OV 9, Reel 4)
      - “Mitteilung des Herausgebers” [h], holograph manuscript
      - “Bibliographie [zur 'Selbstdarstellung']” [circa 1924], holograph manuscript
    - 1925
      - “Notiz über den Wunderblock” [a], holograph manuscript
      - “Sigmund Freud” [“Selbstdarstellung”] [1924] [d]
        - Corrected galley proofs
        - Holograph manuscript, bound
        - Copy published by Felix Meiner Verlag, 52 pp., undated
      - “Die Widerstände gegen die Psychoanalyse” [ 1924 ] [e], holograph manuscript
      - “Geleitwort [Preface to August Aichorn's Verwahrloste Jugend ] [f], photocopy of holograph manuscript
      - “Josef Breuer” [g], holograph manuscript
      - “Die Verneinung” [h], holograph manuscript
      - “Einige psychische Folgen des anatomischen Geschlechtsunterschieds” [j] [ 1926 ], holograph manuscript
    - 1926
      - “Karl Abraham” [b], holograph manuscript
      - “Hemmung, Symptom und Angst” [1925] [d], holograph manuscript
        - Folder 1, pp. 1-38
        - Folder 2, pp. 39-73
      - “Die Frage der Laienanalyse” [e], holograph manuscript
        - Folder 1, pp. 1-42
        - Folder 2, pp. 43-91
      - “Psychoanalysis” [“Psycho-Analysis: Freudian School”] [for the thirteenth edition of the Encyclopaedia Britannica ] [f], holograph manuscript
      - “Noten zur Laienalyse” [1926-1927?], holograph manuscript
      - “Samuel Butler (1835-1902),” holograph manuscript
    - 1927
      - “Nachwort zur Diskussion über 'die Frage der Laienalyse'” [a], holograph manuscript
      - “Nachtrag zum vorstehenden Aufsatz” [“Nachtrag zur Arbeit über den Moses des Michelangelo”] [b], holograph manuscript
      - “Die Zukunft einer Illusion” [c]
        - Holograph manuscript
          - Folder 1, pp. 1-28
          - Folder 2, pp. 28a-51
        - Uncorrected galley proofs
      - “Der Humor” [d], holograph manuscript (Box OV 10, Reel 5)
      - “Fetischismus” [e], holograph manuscript
      - “Fetischismus” and “Der Humor” [d] [e], corrected galley proofs
    - 1929
      - “Ernest Jones zum 50. Geburtstag” [a], holograph manuscript
      - [On his smoking habit], 1929, Feb. 2, typewritten transcript and negative photocopy of holograph manuscript
    - 1929-1939
      - “Kürzeste Chronik,” holograph manuscript
    - 1930
      - “Das Unglück in der Kultur” [“Das Unbehagen in der Kultur”] [1929] [a], holograph manuscript (bound) and photocopy of holograph chapter headings
      - [“Ansprache im Frankfurter Goethe-Haus”] [e]
        - Holograph manuscript
        - Typewritten transcript
        - Clippings of printed version, “Goethe und die Psychoanalyse,” in Neue Freie Presse, 1930, Aug. 29, and “Meine Lebensarbeit” in unidentified serial publication
      - “Vorrede zu der Vorlesungen zur Einführung in die Psychoanalyse,” 1930, Dec., and “Vorrede zu 'Totem und Tabu,'” 1930, Dec., holograph manuscript
    - 1931
      - “Über libidinöse Typen” [a], holograph manuscript
      - “Über die weibliche Sexualität” [b], holograph manuscript
    - 1932
      - “Zur Gewinnung des Feuers” [a], holograph manuscript
      - “An die Vorsitzenden der psychoanalytischen Vereinigungen,” Ostern 1932, holograph manuscript
      - [Max Eitingon], holograph manuscript
    - 1933
      - “Neue Vorlesungen” [“Neue Folge der Vorlesungen zur Einführung in die Psychoanalyse”] [1932] [a], “Vorrede” (typewritten) and holograph manuscript
        - Folder 1, “Vorrede” and pp. 1-32
        - Folder 2, pp. 33-68
        - Folder 3, pp. 69-106
        - Folder 4, pp. 107-144
        - Folder 5, pp. 145-181
    - 1934
      - “Sandor Ferenczi” [c], holograph manuscript
      - “Nachtrag” [1932?], holograph manuscript
      - [Unidentified quotation (for “Neue Vorlesungen XXXI”?)], 1933, Mar. 1, holograph manuscript
    - 1935
      - “Nachschrift” [“Nachschrift 1935 zur 'Selbstdarstellung,'” second edition] [a], holograph manuscript
      - “Die Feinheit einer Fehlhandlung” [b], corrected galley proof (Box OV 11, Reel 5)
    - circa 1935
      - “Chronologie” [bibliography and lists of foreign translations of Freud's writings], holograph manuscript with photocopy
    - 1936
      - [Brief an Romain Rolland]: [“Eine Erinnerungsstörung auf der Akropolis”] [a], holograph manuscript
    - 1937
      - “Lou Andreas-Salomé” [a], holograph manuscript and corrected galley proof
      - “Die endliche und die unendliche Analyse” [c]
        - Holograph manuscript
        - Typewritten manuscript with corrections in Freud's hand
          - Folder 1, pp. 1-18
          - Folder 2, pp. 19-36
          - Folder 3, pp. 37-55
          - Folder 4, pp. 56-73
        - Corrected galley proofs
      - “Konstruktionen in der Analyse” [d]
        - Holograph manuscript
        - Typewritten manuscript with corrections in Freud's hand
      - “Wenn Moses ein Ägypter war ...” [e]
        - Holograph manuscript
          - Folder 1
          - Folder 2
          - Folder 3
        - Corrected galley proofs
    - 1938
      - “Ein Wort zum Antisemitismus” [a], holograph manuscript
      - Letter to the editor of Time and Tide, 1938, Nov. 26 [c], published version
      - [Statement regarding publication of Internationale Zeitschrift für Psychoanalyse ], typewritten manuscript with corrections in Freud's hand
      - [Statement read over British Broadcasting Corp., 1938, Dec.], holograph manuscript
    - 1939 (Box OV 12, Reel 5)
      - [“Der Mann Moses und die monotheistische Religion”] [1937-1939] [a], “Der Mann Moses, Ein Historischer Roman,” holograph manuscript
        - Folder 1, pp. 1-14
        - Folder 2, pp. 15-28[j]
      - “Vorbermerkung I, von dem Marz 1938" [“III: Moses, Sein Volk und die monotheistische Religion”], holograph manuscript
        - Folder 1, pp. 1-32
        - Folder 2, pp. 33-58
        - Folder 3, pp. 59-71
        - Folder 4, pp. 72-88
      - [Translation with Anna Freud of Princess Marie Bonaparte's Topsy, Chow-Chow au Poil d'Or, Paris, 1937, under the title Topsy, der Goldhaarige Chow, Amsterdam] [b], holograph manuscript
        - Folder 1
        - Folder 2
    - 1940 (Box OV 13, Reel 6)
      - “Abriss der Psychoanalyse” [1938] [a], holograph manuscript
        - Folder 1
        - Folder 2
      - “Some elementary lessons in Psycho-Analysis” [1938] [b], holograph manuscript
      - “Das Medusenhaupt” [1922] [c], holograph manuscript
      - “Zur Theorie des hysterischen Anfalles von Dr J. Breuer und Dr Sigm. Freud im Wien” [“With Breuer, Jr, 'Zur Theorie des hysterischen Anfalls'”] [1892] [d], holograph manuscript
      - “Die Ichspaltung im Abwehrvorgang” [1938] [e], holograph manuscript
    - 1941
      - [“Brief an Josef Breuer”], 1892, June 29 [1892] [a], holograph manuscript
      - “III” [“Notiz 'III'”] [1892] [b], holograph manuscript
      - “Eine erfüllte Traumahnung” [1899] [c], holograph manuscript
      - “Vorbericht” [“Psychoanalyse und Telepathie”] [1921] [d]
        - Holograph manuscript
        - Typewritten manuscript with holograph corrections not in Freud's hand
      - [“Ansprache an die Mitgleider des Vereins B'Nai B'rith (1926)”] [1926] [e], holograph manuscript
      - “Ergebnisse, Ideen, Probleme” [1938] [f], holograph manuscript
    - 1942
      - “Psychopathische Personen auf der Bühne” [1905-1906] [a], typewritten transcript and negative photocopy of holograph manuscript
    - 1950
      - [“Entwurf einer Psychologie, 1895"] [Part of “Aus den Anfängen der Psychoanalyse,” 1887-1902] [a], holograph mansucript
        - Folder 1, pp. 1-80
        - Folder 2, pp. 81-100
    - 1951
      - [“A letter on Homosexuality”] [1935] [a], photocopy of holograph manuscript
    - 1955
      - [“Original Record of the Case of Obsessional Neurosis (the 'Rat Man')”] [1907-1908] [a]
        - Holograph manuscript
        - German transcript
      - “Gutachten über eine elektrische Behandlung der Kriegsneurotiker,” 1919-1920 [1920] [c], positive and negative photocopies of holograph manuscript, also transcript and negative photocopy of related background items
    - 1956
      - “Bericht über meine mit Universität-Jubiläums Reisestipendium unternommene Studienreise nach Paris und Berlin, October 1885-Ende März 1886" [1886] [a], negatives and negative prints of holograph manuscript with holograph transcript not in Freud's hand and typewritten transcript
        - Negatives and negative prints of holograph manuscript
        - Holograph transcript not in Freud's hand
        - Typewritten transcripts
    - 1957
      - “Traüme im Folklore,” with Ernst Oppenheim [1911] [a], photocopy of holograph manuscript, including unidentified poetry and writings by someone other than Freud
    - 1966
      - [“Introduction to S. Freud and W. C. Bullitt, Thomas Woodrow Wilson, Twenty-Eighth President of the United States: A Psychological Study ”] [b] [1938], corrected typescript
    - 1985
      - “Übersicht der Übertragungsneurosen” [1915], photocopy of holograph manuscript
    - Undated (Box OV 14, Reel 6)
      - “Abschliessende Bemerkungen,” holograph manuscript
      - [Autobiographical note], holograph manuscript with photocopy
      - “Bemerkungen zu Otto Rank, 'Der Kunstler',” holograph manuscript with photocopy
      - “Citate und Analogien,” photocopy of holograph manuscript
      - [Commentary on an article by Theodor Reik], holograph manuscript
      - “Einige Theoretische Gesichtspunkte zur Paranoia,” photocopy of holograph manuscript with typed transcript
      - [Jahresbilanz], holograph manuscript with photocopy
      - “Kriegswitze” [eleven war jokes], holograph manuscript with typed transcript and photocopy
      - “Meine individuelle Traumcharakteristik (Typische Traüme),” photocopy of holograph manuscript